Guide to the Hoover Institution Archives Photograph Card Catalog
Hoover Institution Archives
- Stone (George E.) Collection, 357 prints / 9 envelopes / 1 negative (Box XX149 - 10.A-V)
  - 16 prints depicting American troops in Europe, 1918-1919 (Box D)
    Includes 1 print of Woodrow Wilson with Poincare; 1 print of General Pershing; 1 print of General Pershing with Marshal Joffre.
  - 16 prints depicting American troops, engineers, and a July 4th parade in Paris, undated (Box E)
    Includes 5 prints of Woodrow Wilson with Clemenceau, Orlando, Lloyd George and General Pershing; 2 prints of Pershing with others.
  - 16 prints depicting American troops, American artillery and the refugees, undated (Box F)
    Includes 1 print of Clemenceau addressing Versailles Conference; 1 print of Major Hardy; 1 print of Grand Trianon, Versailles.
  - 16 prints depicting American troops, German prisoners of war, undated (Box G)
    Includes 1 print of Crucifix in a cathedral at Lucy; 1 print of Woodrow Wilson and party arriving in France.
  - 15 prints depicting American troops arriving in Italy and Austria, undated (Box H)
    Includes 1 print of King George and General Pershing; 1 print of Woodrow Wilson with House, Lansing, White and Bliss; 1 print of a Russian Church; 1 print of a Stanford group.
  - 15 prints depicting American troops pouring into Austria and Germany, undated (Box I)
    Includes 1 print of General Pershing with 7 famous soldiers.
- Story, Russell M. Collection, 8 prints / 1 envelope / 437 glass slides / 6 boxes (Box 57009 - 8.33, 57009 - 10.A-V)
  - 1 print of reception for the Y.M.C.A. American secretaries by the Board of Directors of the Vladivostok Y.M.C.A., Russia; 1 print of Siberian women; 3 prints of the Kremlin, Moscow, October, 1917; 1 print of the Duma Building, Moscow, October 1917; 2 prints of buildings in Moscow, October, 1917
  - 437 glass slides of scenes of Y.M.C.A relief activities and daily life in Russia, 1917-18 (Folder on Shelf 8.33)
- Strench, Mary Minthorn Collection, undated; 1 print / 1 envelope (Box m68051 - 10.A-V)
  Photograph of Henry John Minthorn, Uncle of Herbert Hoover.
- Struve, Gleb Collection, circa 650 prints / 2 albums, 10 envelopes (Box 85018 - 10.A-V)
- Struve, Petr Collection, undated; 52 prints, 2 drawings / 2 envelopes (Box 79083 - 10.A-V)
  - 1 print depicting Petr Struve; 1 print of a drawing depicting Petr Struve, 1937; 1 print depicting Petr Struve in his coffin, 1944; 2 prints depicting a session of the Rossiiskii Zarubezhnyi S'ezd, Paris, 1926; and 2 pencil drawings, one depicting N.E. Markov and the other, Simon Frank (Folder A)
  - 47 prints depicting scenes of the Russian Civil War in the Far East, including in Chita, Irkutsk, and Vladivostok, undated (Folder B)
    Includes prints depicting the American intervention in the Far East.
- Stuart, Graham H. Collection, undated; 1 print / 1 envelope (Box 79097 - 10.A-V Envelope mA)
  1 print depicting G. H Sturat.
- Stuart, Robert Douglas Collection, 6 prints / 1 envelope, 1 oversize box. (Box 84025 - 10.A-V, 84025 -8.14/15)
  - 2 prints depicting General Douglas MacArthur, undated (Folder A)
  - 1 print depicting a B-24 Liberator Bomber of USAF flying above palms of Makin Island; 1 print depicting Herbert Hoover (autographed to R. Douglas Stuart); 1 print depicting the Reunion Dinner of the Industrial Advisory Board, Washington D.C., March 7, 1934; and 1 print depicting a musk ox (Folder 19)
- Stultz (Newell) Collection, undated; 1 envelope / 9 prints (Box 74025 - 10 A-V)
  9 photos of political leaders and activities of the Transkei in South Africa.
- Sullivan, (Mark) Collection, 510 photographs / 3 envelopes (Box 55007 - 10.A-V)
  - 1 glass plate of the tombstone of Isaac and Lydia Pinkham, July 1904 (Folder A)
  - 1 print of Dr. Best University of Toronto, Canada; 2 prints of Dr. Frank Banting; 4 prints of the town of Sarajevo, Serbia, 1914; 3 prints of Mark Sullivan with President Herbert Hoover on cruiser; 1 print of Mark Sullivan 1906; 1 negative (Folder B)
  - 2 prints, 1 negative of Mark Sullivan with his family and former President Herbert Hoover at Avondale, PA, September 1948; 8 prints of Mark Sullivan with President Herbert Hoover's Caribbean cruise; 13 prints of American officers in Europe during World War I; 15 prints of Mark Sullivan, 1935 (Folder C)
- Sullivan (William E.) Collection, 86 prints / 2 envelopes (Box 74049 - 10 A-V Envelope A-B)
  86 photographs of daily life in Philippine Islands, 1920; naval activities at Camp John Hay, Luzon, P.I., 1920; Cultural sites in China; atrocities resulting from 1920-22 uprisings in China; and cultural sites in Guam.
- Sumanis (Vilis) Collection, circa 1924-1938; 29 prints / 1 envelope (Box 70038 - 10.A-V)
  29 photos depicting Latvian Minister, Vilis Sumans and wife, as well as various other Latvian diplomats and their wives in Estonia, Helsinki, Paris, and Rome.
- Surface (Frank M.) Collection, 1917-18 (Box ..... - 9.12)
  4 photos of Herbert Hoover as Food Administrator and 1 photo of Edgar Rickjard (U.S. Food Administration).
- Sviatopolk-Mirsky, N. Collection, undated; 2 prints, 6 postcards / 1 envelope (Box 71026 - 10.A-V)
  Patriotic Russian Imperial postcards, three from the collection of Tsarina Alexandra. Includes a photograph of Tsar Nicholas II and Tsarina Alexandra.
- Swansea, Zuzana Collection, 1968-1990; 75 prints / 1 oversize folder (Box 96039 - map case *mA)
  75 prints of street scenes in Czechoslovakia at the time of Soviet military intervention in 1968 and scenes of subsequent political activity Czechoslovakia.
- Sworakowski, Witold S. Collection, 37 prints / 4 envelopes (Box 79040 - 10.A-V)
  - 2 prints depicting W. S. Sworakowski and another individual, circa 1960s (Folder A)
  - 17 prints of selected Hoover Institution German and Polish Archival and library materials, undated (Folder B)
  - 10 prints depicting World War II destruction in Warsaw, Poland, undated (Folder C)
  - 8 prints depicting World War II atrocities in Poland, undated (Box D)
- Tabor, John Kaye Collection, 1973-1975; 3 prints / 1 envelope (Box 81074 - 1 0.A-V Envelope A)
  Portraits of John K. Tabor, U.S. Under Secretary of Commerce.
- Talbot (Paul Hopkins) Collection, 15 prints / 1 box, 1 oversize (Box 76060 - 8M.02; 10.A-V m*)
  15 prints of officers and crew of several ships such as the USS McLanahan at Boston, Mass, 1919; USS Burns, Pearl Harbor, 1922; USS helm, Portsmouth, VA., 1937. Included is 1 oversize portrait of Adam Talbot.
- Tarsaidze, Alexandre Collection, 404 prints, 51 postcards, 40 duplicates, 2 color transparencies, print negatives and 35mm. black and white negatives, 2 albums / 39 envelopes, 1 album box. (Box 78055 - Photo file)
- Taylor, Alonzo E. Collection, 13 prints / 1 album box, 1 envelope (Box XX267 - 10.A-V, 8M.02)
  - 12 prints depicting American relief activities in Poland following World War I, American Feast in Warsaw, Polish children's kitchen and schools. "In grateful appreciation to Dr. Alonzo Taylor from the children of Poland", Warsaw, 1921 (Folder fA)
  - 1 print depicting Alonzo E. Taylor, undated (Folder mB)
- Telephone, 1916; 1 prints / not in an envelope (Box SX022 - 10.)
  One print depicting the first transmission of a telephone conversation between members of Stanford University and the New York Alumni, upon the occasion of the installation of Ray Lyman Wilbur.
- Telesco (Stephanie E. and Lee) Collection, circa 1941; 1 print / 1 envelope (Box 47006 - 10.)
  1 print of General Courtney Whitney, Chief of the Philippine Section.
- Teller, Edward Collection, 20 prints, 4 contact sheets / 6 envelopes; 15 prints, 5 albums / 2 album boxes; 200 slides / 11 slide boxes (Box 76074 - Photo file, oversize photo file, 8M.02 slide cabinet)
  - 1 print of a portrait of Edward Teller; 1 print depicting Edward Teller's wife Augusta, 1964; 3 contact sheets of prints depicting Edward Teller, undated (Folder A)
  - 7 prints depicting Edward Teller alone and with others, undated (Folder B)
  - 4 prints depicting Edward Teller and General O'Neill at the SAMSO (Space and Missile Systems Organization) Advisory Group luncheon, April, 1968 (Folder C)
  - 1 print depicting Edward Teller and standing next to his portrait and its artists, Eva and Americo Makk; and 4 prints of Eva and America Makk with President Reagan and of their portraits of Ronald and Nancy Reagan, 1984 (Box D)
  - 1 print depicting participants of the Annual Military Research Associate briefing, March 12, 1969; and 1 print of an unidentified scientist at Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory, undated (Box E)
  - 1 contact sheet of prints depicting Leo Szilard, undated (Folder mF)
  - 5 mounted prints of Los Alamos and Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory; 2 prints depicting Edward Teller with others; 1 print depicting Edward Teller with wife Augusta; 5 prints depicting Edward Teller; 1 print depicting a nuclear explosion; and 1 print depicting a crater in Nevada, undated (Folder fG)
  - 5 albums of prints depicting Edward Teller at the Air Force Academy in Colorado Springs, May 12, 1962; at the 101st anniversary celebration of engineering education at Pennsylvania Military College, Philadelphia, April 2, 1963; with J. Robert Oppenheimer and others, 1964; at the Mayo Clinic Centennial Symposium, Rochester, Minnesota, September 17-18, 1964; in South Africa, September 1973 (Folder fH)
  - 200 slides depicting alternate energy sources, 1918 (Folder Slide Boxes 1-11)
- Terleckas, Antanas Collection, 1958-1990; 1 envelope (Box 97054 - 10.A-V Envelope A)
  Prints of protests gatherings in favor of freedom and independence for Lithuania.
- Terry, W. W. Collection, undated; 114 prints / 4 envelopes (Box 92020 - 10.A-V)
  - 17 prints of Salvadorian military personnel and equipment, 1989-1990; 1 print of United Nations personnel, 1989; 3 prints of Alfredo Cristiani, 1989-1990; 3 prints of demonstrators during Cristiani's visit to Washington, D.C., 1990; 4 prints of suspects in National Police headquarters, 1989; 7 prints of patients and staff in a military hospital, 1989-1990; 2 prints of a children's hospital, 1989; 9 prints of various scenes and people in El Salvador, 1989-1990, undated (Folder A)
  - 16 prints of inmates and officials at the women's prison in El Salvador, 1989; 1 print of Jennifer Casolo in the prison, 1989; 21 prints relating to the raid on Jennifer Casolo, including photographs of confiscated weapons, a religious service, FMLN personnel, Casolo, Peter Yarrow and others, 1989, undated (Folder B)
  - 6 prints of John Hull with others, 1988-1991; 7 prints of facilities and airstrips at the Hull ranch in Costa Rica, 1988; 6 prints of the Hull house with associates, 1988; 7 prints of various scenes, individuals, and associates of John Hull, including John Singlaub and others, 1988-1990; 3 prints of a Costa Rican refugee camp, 1988, undated (Folder C)
  - 1 print depicting a Nicaraguan "Contras" training camp, undated (Folder D)
- Thompson (Dorothy) Collection, 226 prints / 3 envelopes (Box 69046 - 10.A-V)
  - 29 prints depicting schools and rural scenes in Greece, Nice, Geneva, North Africa, and Czechoslovakia, circa 1937 (Folder A)
  - 105 prints depicting Italian scenes of schools, Mussolini, Victor Emmanuel, Rome, and children, circa 1936 (Folder B)
  - 92 prints depicting Rumanian schools, factories, cities, rural areas, and government officials, circa 1936 (Folder C)
- Thompson, Paul J. Collection, September 1918; 1 envelope / 9 prints (Box m34007 - 10.A-V)
  Photographs of Italian prisoners of war held by Austria, taken at the time of their release.
- Thompson, Virginia McLean Collection, 22 prints / 2 envelopes (Box XX171 - 10.A-V)
  - 5 prints of scenes in the Congo (Brazzaville), including 4 depicting President Fulbert Youlou, circa 1959-1963 (Folder A)
  - 17 prints of scenes in Madagascar, including government officials and visiting diplomats; commemoration ceremonies for Madagascar soldiers killed in World War II; and a painting of Queen Ranavalona II, undated (Folder B)
- Thorpe, Steve Collection, undated; 150 prints / 1 envelope (Box 81068 - 10.A-V Envelope A)
  Depicts student demonstrations at Xinan Lianhe Daxue (Southwest Associated University), Kunming, China, protesting the killing of four students at the University by Kuomintang soldiers in 1945.
- Tittle, Walter Collection, undated; 25 drawings / 1 package (Box XX331 - 8.29)
  25 portraits by Walter Tittle, 1922, of American, British, Japanese, French, Italian, Belgian and Chinese delegates to the Washington Conference for the Limitation of Armaments of 1921-1922. Portraits are autographed by their subjects.
- Titulescu (Nicolas) Collection, undated; 1 prints / 1 envelope (Box 74098 - 10.A-V)
  1 print (photograph of a portrait) of Nicolas Titulescu.
- Todd, Oliver J. Collection, circa 7,000 prints, postcards, slides, negatives / 16 boxes (Boxes 60-75) (Box 73087 - 8.19)
- Toegel, Stanislaw Collection, 1905-1946 (Box 89075 - Slide Cabinet)
  23 slides (1 slide box) depicting political cartoons, 1945, satirizing Adolf Hitler and other German Nazi leaders, and depicting the plight of Poland under German occupation.
- Tolstaia (Maria A.) Collection, 1905-1942; 13 prints / 1 envelope (Box 80179 - 10.A-V)
  Family photographs depicting individuals in Russia and emigration.
- Trainor (Joseph C.) Collection, 83 prints / 2 envelopes (Box 72022 - 8M.36)
  - 40 prints depicting services provided to the employees by the Toyo Kogyo Kabushiki Kaisha (a Japanese construction plant in Hiroshima) and conditions of Tokyo school buildings affected by the Atom Bomb explosion, and depicting conditions of Hiroshima school buildings affected by the Atom Bomb explosion, undated (Folder A)
  - 43 prints depicting Japanese educational techniques in progress, April, 1949 (Folder B)
- Treat (Payson J.) Collection, 169 prints, 6 negs. / 7 env. / 219 prints in 1 album. (Box 60003 - 10.A-V)
  - 6 photos (negatives) of Joseph Stalin, undated (Folder A)
  - 13 photos of Manchurian government officials, 1930's (Folder B)
  - 32 photos of daily life and cultural sites in Manchuria, China, and Japan, undated (Folder C)
  - 35 photos of P.J. Treat with his wife during trips to Japan with friends and colleagues, and receiving an award, 1920 and 1935 (Box D)
  - 1 rare Japanese print from a copper plate, undated (Box E)
  - 3 oversize photos of P.J. Treat with colleagues including Ephraim D. Adams and Yamoto Ichihashi, of the negotiators of the Russo-Japanese treaty in 1905, and of a Chinese execution, undated (Folder mF)
  - 219 photos in 1 album and 79 loose photos pertaining to P.J. Treat's trip to the Far East, 1930's (?) (Folder G, fG)
- Trotsky Collection, 49 prints / 4 envelopes (Box 92032 - 10.A-V)
  - 8 prints of Leon Trotsky and his wife, Natalia Sedova Trotskaia, In Mexico. Prints autographed by Trotskaia, undated (Folder A)
  - 15 prints of Evelyn Reed and guards and other members of the Trotsky household at the villa of Leon Trotsky in Coyoacan, Mexico, 1940 (Folder B)
  - 25 prints of the villa of Leon Trotsky in Coyo9acan, Mexico, showing fortification and other security measures, 1940 (Folder C)
  - 1 print, incompletely identified, take on the ocean liner "Normandie", possibly of Ramon Mercader, undated (Box D)
- Tupper, Gene Collection, 1969; 13 prints / 1 envelope (Box 80043 - 10.A-V)
  Depicts radical student posters and demonstrations at Stanford University.
- Turauskas (Eduardas) Collection, June-July 1941; 42 prints / 1 envelope (Box 75015 - 10.A-V)
  40 photographs depicting atrocities committed by Soviet forces in Lithuania. Included are 2 photographs of Aniceta Stoucinte.
- Turner (Robert F.) Collection, 235 photos / 74 negatives (on 10 filmstrips) (17 envelopes, 1 album) (Box 74040 - 10.A-V)
- Tyrmand, Leopold Collection, 11 photographs / 4 envelopes (Box 86015 - 10.A-V)
  - 4 photos of Leopold Tyrmand, 1970 (Folder A)
  - 1 photo of John A. Howard, undated (Folder B)
  - 1 photo of drawing by Zbginiew Fitz, undated (Folder C)
  - 5 photos of New Orleans jazz clubs, undated (Box D)
- United Nations. Conference on International Organization, San Francisco, Pictorial Works. Collection, 1945; circa 250 prints / 5 envelopes (Box 47026 - 10.A-V Envelope A-D, mE)
  Photographs depicting delegates to, and scenes at, the conference organizing the United Nations at San Francisco.
- U. S. Army Signal Corps Collection, 1 album / 1 envelope / 11 oversize photos (Box 50012 - 10.A-V)
  - An album of Signal Corps photographs, depicting A.E.F. activities in France during World War I, including many individual and group portraits of senior officers, and a few photographs of the A.E.F. in England and Germany, 1917-1919 (Folder f)
  - 8 photographs of A.E.F. activities in France and the U.S, undated (Folder A)
  - 11 photographs of the A.E.F. activities in France and the U.S, undated (Folder m)
- U.S. Committee on Puiblic Information (Washington D.C.) Collection, undated (Box 62010 - 10.A-V)
  - Photographs, depicting the activities of the A.E.F. in the U.S. and France during World War I, including scenes of training, and naval and aerial operations. Photographs are unlabeled, undated (Folder A-H)
  - 2 oversize aerial photos and 4 copies of paintings depicting battle scenes in World War I, and 1 liberty loan poster, undated (Folder m dr. 2)
- U.S. Economic Cooperation Administration Collection, circa 1948-1951; 3 prints / 1 envelope (Box XX679 - 10.A-V)
  Depicts communist and anti-communist posters in Paris.
- United States Food Administration Collection, undated; 110 prints / 5 envelopes (Box XX066 - 10.A-V)
  - 55 prints of the following FA personnel: Julius H. Barnes, Charles Harvey Bentley, Dr. Alice Boughton, John M. Bowman, Edward Chambers, James Collins, Crowell, Edward M. Flesh, Dr. Harry Augustus Garfield, Hugh Gibson, Virginia C. Gildersleeve, H.B. Grose, Beatrice Forbes Robertson Hale, John W. Hallowwell, George E. Haskell, E.O. Heyl, Hilyer, Holman, Vernon Kellogg, Katherine Leckie, Curtis H. Lindley, John F. Lucey, Charles M. McCarthy, Duncan McDuffie, Howard McLenahan, C.E. Raymond, Mark Lawrence Requa, Edgar Rickard, George M. Rolph, Josephine Roche, Lou D. Sweet, Robert Taft, Dr. Alonzo Taylor, Dr. Ray Lyman Wilbur, Frederic C. Walcot, Theodore Whitmarsh, undated (Folder A)
  - 8 prints of women volunteers, 1 miscellaneous print, undated (Folder B)
  - 13 prints of FA staff groups and publicity, undated (Folder mC)
  - 23 prints depicting FA publicity signs in various American cities, undated (Folder D-mE)
- U.S. Maritime Service Collection, undated; 5 albums (Box fXX271 - 10.AV Album A-E)
  Photographs depicting activities of the U.S. Maritime Service during World War II, including training and medical examination of merchant seamen, and provision of recreational facilities for them. 5 albums.
- U.S. National Student Association Collection, undated; 692 prints, 27 negatives / 7 envelopes (Box 68011 - 8.44-48 - 10.A-V)
  A-E, mF, mG
- U.S. President's Famine Emergency Committee. Collection, 1946-1947; 137 prints / 2 envelopes (Box XX177 - 9.16/17, XX177 - 10.A-V)
  - 117 prints of Herbert Hoover and others on the European and Asian Food Missions of the Famine Emergency Committee. Countries visited included Greece, Iran, Yugoslavia, Belgium, Egypt, China, Switzerland, India, Norway, Japan and Thailand, 1946-1947 (Folder A)
  - 20 United Press International reprints of officials and activities of the U.S. President's Famine Emergency Committee, 1946-1947 (Folder B)
- University of Hawaii Collection, 1,271 prints / 28 envelopes (Box XX232 - 10.A-V)
- Universum Film Aktiengesellschaft (UFA) Collection, 151 prints / 3 envelopes (Box 48007 - 10 A-V)
  - 130 photos of Germany military forces on maneuvers, in military parades, and during invasions of the low countries, France, North Africa, and Russia, 1940 (Folder A-B)
    Includes photos of munitions factory workers.
  - 21 photos of NAZI leaders, including Hitler, Hess, Goering, Goebbels, Donetz, and Rader, undated (Folder C)
    Includes photos of Mussolini.
- Usher (George L.) Collection, 181 photos / 3 envelopes (Box 69081 - 10 A-V Envelope A-C)
  181 photos dealing with World War I German aircraft and military reconnaissance activities in France. Includes photos of early American aircraft 1909 and scenes of Vera Cruz, 1914.
- Utley, Freda Collection, 127 prints, 26 negatives / 11 envelopes (Box 78056 - 10.A-V)
  - 10 prints of Freda Utley, alone, and with others, including William F. Buckley, Jr., and Walter Judd, circa 1930s-1970s (Folder A)
  - 9 prints of Freda Utley and her brother Temple as children, and of their parents, undated (Folder B)
  - 6 prints, including 1 of Arcadi Berdichevsky, husband of Freda Utley, circa 1935, and 5 of Freda Utley and her son Jon, circa 1930s-1970s (Folder C)
  - 10 prints and postcards of war damage and other scenes in Germany, and German acquaintances of Freda Utley, circa 1940s-1950s (Box D)
  - 12 prints of scenes in China, including military scenes from the Sino Japanese War; Freda Utley in China; and Chinese acquaintances, including Chou En-lai, circa 1938-1956 (Box E)
  - 20 U.S. Army and navy prints of American military activities in Vietnam, 1966-1967 (Box F)
    Includes portraits of General William C. Westmoreland and Lieutenant General Bruce Palmer Jr.
  - 9 prints and postcards of scenes in Egypt, and Freda Utley with King Faisal of Saudi Arabia and President Gamal Abdel Nasser of Egypt, 1918-1970s (Box G)
    Includes 3 portraits of President Anwar Sadat of Egypt and his family.
  - 27 prints made by the United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees of Palestine Refugees of Palestinian refugees in Jordan and the Gaza Strip and of relief work on their behalf, 1959 (Box H)
  - 17 prints, of Arab war refugees and of Arab civilian victims of Israeli bombing, 1967 (Box I)
  - 7 miscellaneous or unidentified prints and postcards, 1934 (Box J)
    Includes 1 print of the sailing ship of Freda Utley's brother Temple.
  - 26 unidentified negatives, undated (Box K)
- Vaizey, John Ernest Collection, 69 prints / 4 envelopes (Box 86017 - 10.A-V)
  - 20 portrait prints of Hugh Dalton, undated (Folder A)
  - 30 prints of Hugh Dalton; 1 print of A. Guiness, circa 1882 (reproduction); 1 print of a painting of John Foster, Baron O'Neil, circa 18th century, undated (Folder B)
  - 5 group photographs, including Hugh Dalton, Clement Attlee, Ernest Bevin, Winston Churchill, Jawaharlal Nehru, other Cabinet ministers (?), circa 1945-1947; 4 prints of Hugh Dalton and colleagues in ceremonial robes; 4 prints of Hugh Dalton at a political march in Durham, 1956; 2 prints of Hugh Dalton in a presentation ceremony, 1947 (Folder C)
  - 2 portrait prints of Hugh Dalton, undated (Folder mD)
- Valentinov (Nikolai V.) Collection, undated; 9 photos / 1 envelope (Box 65003 - 10.A-V)
  1 photograph of N. (Valentinov) Volsky, 4 prints of S. Prokopovich, and 1 print each of Iu. Dalin, Lydia Dan, A. N. Potresov, and Elena Osipovna Stensel.
- Van Hook (Clifford E.) Collection, 1933-34; 1 print / 1 envelope (Box 76030 - 10.A-V Envelope m)
  One photograph of the Army War College Class depicting Rear Admiral Clifford E. Van Hook with a group of naval officers.
- Van Keuren (Alexander H.) Collection, 337 prints / 1 negative / 7 envelopes / 1 folder (Box 74011 - 10.A-V)
  - 274 prints, 1 negative depicting various locations and persons in A. Van Keuren's naval career, 1903-1946 (Folder m* A-D)
  - 10 prints depicting the British Radar Mission visit to the Naval Research Laboratory, Chesapeake Bay Annex, Dec 18, 1943 (Folder E-F)
  - 43 prints of A.H. Van Keuren, 1904-1965 (Box G)
- Vardy, Alexander Collection, undated; 5 prints / 1 envelope (Box 91014 - Photo file)